hey guys today i'm going to do a how to
tint your brows at home using a brand
that i've just picked up from hairways
i'm using natural brown which is shade
number three
they do deeper shades for darker hair
and lighter shades if you're fairer i
find the natural brown is the one that
gives me the ashiest tone i only tend to
tint my brows when i'm going on holiday
i take a dappen dish which is a clear
little glass pop and i usually mix
between one and a half to two
centimeters and i give it a good mix in
the pot before i put in the developer
so this is the cream developer that i
use with the reflector seal again both
can be found in hairways or online and
this one is three percent which is ten
vowel for one centimeter of refector
seal you need eight to ten drops of the
oxidant
you want to mix that really really well
so that you get a nice thick consistency
and it's really important that you
always do a patch test on yourself and
this should be done either behind your
ear or on the bend of your elbow and if
you don't react within 48 to 72 hours
then you are good to use the tin if you
do have any red blotchiness then you
shouldn't use it
by the way i should mention this is not
a sponsored tutorial refector seal is
the brand that my twin sister uses on me
so i know i like it i don't react to it
so i always use this one now i like a
super light tint this is my natural
brows if you like it stronger and you
want it to take longer leave it on for
the full 10 minutes but i do mine in
small increments so i take an orange
wood stick and i apply this to the brow
pushing it into the hair so it touches
the skin and also make sure that you
touch both sides of your hair that way
it will really take on the tint
the great thing about tinting your brows
is that it will stain your skin which
means that your brow will naturally look
slightly darker where you don't have
hair and those tiny white vellus hairs
that you can't see will also take on the
tint making them look fuller
also don't worry about being messy at
this stage you just want to get the tint
on and then we're going to clean up the
edges
to do so i'm taking a damp cotton bud
and i'm creating a nice crisp line on
the base of my eyebrow i'm also going to
do the same along the top
and then also along the arch and the
tail of the eyebrow as well
now as i mentioned i like a really light
natural tint it'll also show up a little
bit more defined when i'm not in studio
lighting i tend to take my tint off
after just one minute because my hair
really grabs with tin and then if i need
it to be a little bit darker i will then
repeat the same process i'd rather that
than my brows getting too dark too quick
i start by using a cotton bud to wipe
off the excess product
then i go in with a damp cotton pad and
i work that right between the hair to
make sure i've completely removed the
tin
you'll see i've got subtle stain into
the skin and the hair is a bit darker so
i'm going to repeat the process again
and just leave it on for one extra
minute you'll know i love a very natural
eyebrow but for those of you that like
it a little bit more intense you can
leave it on for the full 10 minutes
so as you can see from my before and
after what i've got is a really nice
natural result this is how my brows look
when they've been filled in with a
pencil and this will last me two to four
weeks
so i hope you found that useful and
informative please share this with any
of your light eyebrow friends that need
a tint that are fed up with penciling
them in day after day please give the
tutorial a thumbs up if you enjoyed it
don't forget to hit the subscribe button
and the notification bell so you don't
miss any of my uploads if you'd like to
follow me outside of youtube my social
handles are on screen thank you so much
for watching and i'll see you again soon
bye